Richard Halliburton Papers, 1900-1973: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1900-1946; 7 boxes (1 partial)
  - Letters Regarding Rupert Brooke, 1912-1946; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    - To Richard Halliburton, 1912-1946; 51 folders
      - Hornby, Hon. (St. John), 1927; 1 folder (Folder 37)
      - Kelly, Mary, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 38)
      - Keynes, Geoffrey, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 39)
      - Lindsay, Gertrude, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 40)
      - Lucas, F.L., 1912; 1 folder (Folder 41)
      - Lucas, St. John, 1928; 1 folder (Folder 42)
      - Macauley, Rose, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 43)
      - Mansel, Muriel, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 44)
      - McClelland and Stewart, 1933; 1 folder (Folder 45)
      - McHugh, Kay, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 46)
      - Mirril, Maurice, undated; 1 folder (Folder 47)
      - Nesbitt, Cathleen, undated; 1 folder (Folder 48)
      - Nevinson, Henry W., undated; 1 folder (Folder 49)
      - Nichols, Beverly, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 50)
      - Pye, Sybil, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 51)
      - Richards, Noel Olivier, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 52)
      - Robertson, D.H., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 53)
      - Salter, Helen M.G., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 54)
      - Scott, Winfield, undated; 1 folder (Folder 55)
      - Sherrand, Brynhild, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 56)
      - Sidgewick, Frank, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 57)
      - Thompson, Sydenham, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 58)
      - Volk, Conrad (Clayton Grey), 1927; 1 folder (Folder 59)
      - Ward, Dudley, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 60)
      - Watson, El Grant, undated; 1 folder (Folder 61)
      - Waugh, Alec, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 62)
      - Williams, Iolo A., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 63)
      - Woolf, Virginia, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 64)
      - Unidentified Sources, 1927-1928; 1 folder (Folder 65)
      - Stringer, Arthur, 1946; 1 folder (Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1900-1939; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    - By Richard Halliburton, 1900-1939; 19 folders
      - Chamber, Lawrence, 1925-1938; 14 folders (Folder 1-14)
      - Halliburton, Wesley, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Halliburton, Richard, 1900-1939; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Singer, Frances, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Stetson, D. D., Mrs., undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Stuck, Charles A., undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - To Richard Halliburton, 1927-1928; 10 folders
      - Lawrenceville School Headmaster, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - Goodrich, Rear Admiral, US Navy, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      - Watson, Hy. S., undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - R. Halliburton's Publishers, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - A-G (fan mail), 1927-1928; 2 folders (Folder 24-25)
      - H-Z (fan mail), 1927-1928; 3 folders (Folder 1-3)
      - Unidentified Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Bennett, F.J. to Captain R.W. Tucker of the S.S. Ipswich, 1921; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Recommendation.
    - Halliburton Trans-Pacific Chinese Junk Expedition, Inc., to P. L. Williams, 1939 January 18-February 16; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      3 mimeographed letters and 2 small photographs with accompanying official envelopes.
- Series 3: Biographical Materials, 1909-1973; 4 boxes (1 partial)
  Arranged into three subseries by material type.
  This series consists of personal documents, clippings of articles and other printed materials about Halliburton's life and travels, and various memorabilia he kept, such as event programs, clippings, maps, and artwork.
  - Subseries 3A: Documents, 1918 December 21-1934; 4 folders
    This subseries consists of personal documents belonging to Richard Halliburton, including an official term report from Princeton University, two passports, a Montana fishing license, and publishing contracts.
    - Princeton University Official Term Report, 1918 December 21; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      For naval training.
    - Passports, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Fishing License - Montana, 1920; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      Two passports.
    - Publishers' Contracts, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3B: Richard Halliburton as Subject, 1920 February 28-1973; 15 folders
    This subseries consists of writings and clippings about Richard Halliburton's travels, including an announcement for his election to Associate Editor of The Lawrence, a Vanity Fair article titled "We nominate For Oblivion: R.H.," as well as other printed materials regarding Richard Halliburton.
    - Announcement - Election of R.H. as Associate Editor of the Lawrence, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - The Daily Printsanything, 1920 February 28; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Around the World with Dick Halliburton Holmes, The Omelet, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - The Omelet, 1922 June; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Summary of Halliburton's Travels in Latin America; pr., 1928; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Vanity Fair, 1930 June. "We nominate For Oblivion: R.H.", 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - The Broadcaster, 1933; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Promotion Bill, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - "The Glorious Adventure by Richard Halliburton", by Edward Donahoe, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Daily Sketch, 1935 July 23; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Printed Material regarding Burton Holmes, 1941-1942; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Life's Odyssey Ends for Richard Halliburton. The Commercial Appeal, Memphis, Tenn. Sun., 1939 June 11; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Published Short Biographies, 1953; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Halliburton Gift to Aid Princeton, 1966; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Deffaa Clippings, 1973; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Subseries 3C: Memorabilia, 1909-1947; 14 folders
    This subseries contains various memorabilia kept by Richard Halliburton, including Class Day and graduation programs from Princeton University, clippings, and other printed materials, as well as a collection of maps and tourist guides documenting locations Halliburton visited, some artwork he collected, and miscellaneous notes and addresses.
    - Dryburgh Abbey: Its Monks and Its Lords, 1909; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Lend me Five Shillings - Theater Program, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Class Day and Graduation Programs, 1917-1921; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - His Name was Mudd, George Allan England, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1920-1943; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Notes and Addresses, circa 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Maps, 1930-1947; 6 folders
      - Tourist Maps and Guidebooks (United States), circa 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Tourist Maps and Guidebooks (International), circa 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        Includes materials, titled "Tunisie," "Bali," "Vierwaldstattersee," "Deutschland, Oesterreich, der Schweiz and angrenzenden Landern," "Switzerland," "Rheinlauf," "Short Guide to Bali," largely geared towards tourists.
      - National Geographic Maps, 1943-1947; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        Original folder also marked "Story of Richard's Com. Appeal." Includes National Geographic maps titled "Europe and the Near East," "Pacific Ocean and the Bay of Bengal," "Southeast Asia and Pacific Islands from the Indies and the Philippines to the Solomons," "Germany and Its Approaches," "The World," "Bible Lands and the Cradle of Western Civilization," "The United States of America," "Countries of the Caribbean Including Mexico," "Central America and the West Indies," and "Japan and Korea."
      - "New Worlds" Maps, circa 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        Includes maps titled "The Countries of the Caribbean including Mexico, Central America, the West Indies and the Panama Canal," "A Plan of the City, and Lake of Mexico" (annotated), "West Indies," "Cuba, Jamaica, and the Bahama Islands," "Panama" (annotated), and a large 5 x 3 foot linen-mounted map titled "Mapa de la Republica de Panama," which contains annotations regarding Halliburton's travels through Panama and the Panama Canal.
      - "A New Yorker's View of the United States of America" Map, circa 1930s; AM 2003-124; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        Inscribed to Richard Halliburton.
      - "The Route of the Flying Carpet" Maps, circa 1930s; AM 2003-124; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        Two hand-drawn maps.
    - William von Gloeden, "Cain" Etching, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Artworks by Others, undated; 1 box
      Consists of several large, rolled artworks, including a drawing of "La Cite de Carcassonne," photographs of Mount Olympus and the Parthenon, and other materials.
- Series 4: Photographs, 1918-1939; 24 boxes (2 partial)
  Arranged into two subseries.
  This series consists of a significant group of photographic materials extensively documenting Halliburton's international travels in the Americas, Europe, Asia, and Africa, including journeys described in his published books, and to a lesser extent his friends at Princeton and his home. Black-and-white photographic prints, nitrate and acetate negatives, glass show slides, and glass plate negatives are all present. While photographic materials have been physically stored by type for preservation purposes, they are listed by subject in the finding aid.
  - Subseries 4A: Photographs Related to His Works, 1919-1939; 19 boxes (6 partial)
    Arranged into file groups by work.
    This subseries includes photographic materials documenting Halliburton's extensive travels in the Americas, Europe, Asia, and Africa as described in his published works.
    - The Flying Carpet, 1930-1939; 10 boxes (7 partial)
      - Baghdad, 1930-1932; portions of 3 boxes
        - Baghdad, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 2 folders (Folder 1-2)
        - Baghdad, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Baghdad, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 9 4 x 5" and 2 5 x 7" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Bali, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Bali, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Bali, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Borneo, 1930-1932; portions of 4 boxes
        - Borneo, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 4 folders (Folder 4-7)
        - Borneo, "Heads Given by Chief of Headhunters in Borneo" Photograph, circa 1930-1932; 1 oversize photograph 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Borneo, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 2 folders (Folder 3-4)
        - Borneo, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 16 5 x 7" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Egypt, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Egypt, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Egypt, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Elly Beinhorn, 1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Elly Beinhorn, Photographs, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Elly Beinhorn, Negatives, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Europe, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Europe, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Europe, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Flying Carpet Departs, Photographs, 1930; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        Includes photographs of Pancho Barnes and Moye Stephens.
      - Foreign Legion, 1931; portions of 3 boxes
        - Foreign Legion, Photographs, 1931; 2 folders (Folder 2-3)
        - Foreign Legion, Negatives, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Foreign Legion, Glass Plate Negatives and Positive, 1931; 8 5 x 7" glass plate negatives and 1 3 x 4" glass plate color positive 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Greece, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Istanbul, 1930-1932; portions of 3 boxes
        - Istanbul, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Istanbul, Oversize Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Istanbul, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - In and Near Persia, 1930-1932; portions of 4 boxes
        - In and Near Persia, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
        - In and Near Persia, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - In and Near Persia, Persepolis, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - In and Near Persia, Tehran Prison, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - In and Near Persia, Babylon, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - In and Near Persia, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 8 5 x 7" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - In and Near Persia, Broken Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 2 broken 5 x 7" glass plate negatives portion of 1 box
          Broken glass plate negatives were encapsulated in archival plexiglass to facilitate handling.
      - Java, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Jerusalem, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Jerusalem, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Jerusalem, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Manila, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Morocco, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Morocco, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Morocco, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Mountains, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Mountains, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 4)
          Includes photographs of the Matterhorn, Mount Everest, and Darjeeling, India.
        - Mountains, Darjeeling, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Mountains, Everest, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Petra, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Petra, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Petra, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Sahara, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Sahara, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Sahara, Negative, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Samarra, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Sea of Galilee, 1930-1932; portions of 3 boxes
        - Sea of Galilee, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Sea of Galilee, "Fishermen" Photograph, circa 1930-1932; 1 oversize photograph 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Sea of Galilee, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - Taj Mahal, 1930-1932; portions of 3 boxes
        - Taj Mahal, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Taj Mahal, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Taj Mahal, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 11 4 x 5" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Timbuctoo, 1930-1932; portions of 2 boxes
        Tombouctou (Mali).
        - Timbuctoo, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Timbuctoo, Negatives, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Turkey, Photographs, circa 1930-1932; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - "Sundry Negatives", 1939; Damaged acetate negatives 3 folders (Folder 1-3)
        Includes 26 damaged 8 x 10" acetate negatives, mailed in 1939. Duplicates of images filed by location.
    - The Glorious Adventure, 1925-1927; portions of 6 boxes
      - Athens, 1925-1927; portions of 5 boxes
        - Athens, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Athens, Oversize Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Athens, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Athens, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 6 5 x 7" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Athens, Broken Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 2 broken 5 x 7" glass plate negatives portion of 1 box
      - Corfu, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Delphi and Parnassus, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Delphi and Parnassus, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Delphi and Parnassus, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Greece, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Hellespont, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Hellespont, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Hellespont, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Ithaca, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Olympus, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Olympus, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Olympus, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Palmyra and Baalbec, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Palmyra and Baalbec, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Palmyra and Baalbec, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Taormina, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Tempe, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Tempe, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Tempe, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Troy, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Troy, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Troy, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Wonders of the World, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Wonders of the World, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Wonders of the World, Negatives, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Works of Art, 1925-1927; portions of 2 boxes
        - Works of Art, Photographs, circa 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Works of Art, Head of Hermes of Praxiteles Photograph, circa 1925-1927; 1 oversize photograph 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - New Worlds to Conquer, 1928-1929; 7 boxes (5 partial)
      - Devil's Island, 1928-1929; 4 boxes (3 partial)
        - Devil's Island, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Devil's Island, Oversize Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 3 folders (Folder 1-3)
        - Devil's Island, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Devil's Island, Damaged Negatives, circa 1928-1929; Damaged acetate negatives 1 folder (Folder 4)
          Includes 4 damaged acetate negatives. Duplicates.
      - Iguazu Falls, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        Also includes a guidebook.
      - Inland South America, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Machu Picchu, 1928-1929; portions of 2 boxes
        - Machu Picchu, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Machu Picchu, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Maximilian, Carlota, Cortés, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Mexico, 1928-1929; portions of 2 boxes
        - Mexico, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Mexico, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Monkey, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Panama Canal, 1928-1929; portions of 2 boxes
        - Panama Canal, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Panama Canal, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Panama and Central America, 1928-1929; portions of 3 boxes
        - Panama and Central America, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Panama and Central America, Landscape Photograph, circa 1928-1929; 1 oversize photograph 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Panama and Central America, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Peru and Juan Fernandez, 1928-1929; portions of 3 boxes
        - Peru and Juan Fernandez, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Peru and Juan Fernandez, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - Peru and Juan Fernandez, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 5 7 x 9.5" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Robinson Crusoe, 1928-1929; portions of 3 boxes
        - Robinson Crusoe, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
        - Robinson Crusoe, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Robinson Crusoe, Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 16 8 x 10" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Vera Cruz to Mexico City, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Well of Death, 1928-1929; portions of 2 boxes
        - Well of Death, Negatives, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - Well of Death, Photographs, circa 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Royal Road to Romance, 1919-1935; portions of 5 boxes
      - Agrrides, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - Agrrides, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Agrrides, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Angkor, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - Angkor, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Angkor, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - China and Japan, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - China and Japan, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - China and Japan, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - France, 1919-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - France, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - France, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Germany, 1919-1933; portions of 2 boxes
        - Germany, Photographs, circa 1919-1933; 1 folder (Folder 2)
          Includes a small group of Hitler propaganda postcards.
        - Germany, Negatives, circa 1919-1933; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Gibraltar, 1922; portions of 2 boxes
        - Gibraltar, Photographs, circa 1922; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Gibraltar, Negatives, circa 1922; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Holland, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - Holland, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Holland, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - India, 1919-1925; portions of 3 boxes
        - India, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - India, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - India, Glass Plate Negative, circa 1919-1925; 1 5 x 7" glass plate negative 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Kashmir, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - Kashmir, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
        - Kashmir, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Leh, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - London, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - London, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - London, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Malay and Siam, 1919-1925; portions of 2 boxes
        - Malay and Siam, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Malay and Siam, Negatives, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Matterhorn, 1921; portions of 2 boxes
        - Matterhorn, Photographs, circa 1921; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Matterhorn, Negatives, circa 1921; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Spain, 1922; portions of 2 boxes
        - Spain, Photographs, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Spain, Negatives, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Venice, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Zagi Pass, Photographs, circa 1919-1925; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Promotional Photographs, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        Includes photographs of Richard Halliburton in front of bookstore windows containing his book displays.
    - Seven League Boots, 1932-1935; 7 boxes (6 partial)
      - Arabia, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Arabia, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Arabia, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Assassination, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Athos, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Bones of Columbus, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Bones of Columbus, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - Bones of Columbus, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Christophe's Citadel, 1934; portions of 2 boxes